Barrett Quan

Los Angeles, CA, 91006

21barrett@gmail.com Phone: (626) 731-2327

github.com/yeahbq // linkedin.com/in/barrettquan // barrettquan.com

Summary

A driven and determined Full Stack Web Developer transitioning from a sports coaching career. Coming from a coaching background, I excel in working in a team environment including technical and non-technical members.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, git, GitHub, deployment through Heroku, Node.js, Express, RESTful web services, React, Angular.js, command line, Bash, mongoDB/mongoose, postgresql, Handlebars, UI/UX wireframes, Zeplin.io, responsive web design, agile development and SCRUM methodology.

Projects

Virtual – Pests (Virtual Pet Simulator)

Experience a blast from the past as you feed, train and clean up your VPESTS. Written in Angular and used services and to manage button clicks and backend server requests.

Dinder (Dinner Finder)

Swipe through suggested businesses based off current location. Using yelp's api to provide the search results, and saving likes to a database based on user login. Worked on as a small four-person team as SCRUM master that fostered teamwork and practiced constant communication through facilitating standups.

Sports Team Roster Manager

Enter your sports team and roster into the site, where it can then be displayed, edited and deleted. Built with JavaScript, node.js, MongoDB, and Handlebars.js templates for client side rendering.

Connect Four

Play connect four taking turns with a friend on a traditional 7 x 6 board. Built in JavaScript and renders the website using code made from HTML and CSS files.

Experience

Volleyball Coach, 2013-Present, Gabrielino High School

Inspired youth to master new information and techniques to apply in and out of game situations. Interact with players in fun and meaningful ways to encourage individual growth.

Volleyball Coach, 2013-Present, Starlings San Gabriel

Understand youth culture to organize and plan tryouts for eligible players from all over the San Gabriel Valley. Also attended monthly facility meetings with the city of San Gabriel to reserve gyms to use as practice sites. Coached team to implement high level skills and decision making in competitive SCVA hosted tournaments.

Education

General Assembly

Certificate of completion, Web Development Immersive Program Nov 2016 – March 2017

Biola University

B.A. Journalism (Broadcast Communications) 2006 -2010

Hobbies and Miscellaneous

Basketball, Volleyball, E-Sports, cooking up Milk Tea / Boba, and Photography.